本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： leslie仙仙 媚子 小飞鱼 魔法莉露姆 Smile176
校对/后期： 海之南
成长于八十年代
Growing up in the '80s,
我不仅仅是热爱电影 更是活在其中
I didn't just love movies-- I lived them.
也许稍有点过了
Maybe a little too much.
嘿 小家伙
Hey, little buddy.
嘿 巴里 想加入我的电影吗
Hey, Barry. You want to be in my movie?
乐意之极
I'd love nothing more.
好 我在游戏网格线里
Okay, so I'm inside the game grid,
我有这些身份磁盘 你要...
and I have these identity discs, and you're gonna...
收工了 呆子
That's a wrap, nerd.
我们街道上没有孩子和我一起玩
I had no kids on my street to play with,
而我的哥哥姐姐对我的爱好
and my older siblings weren't exactly interested
不那么感兴趣
in my hobbies.
呦
Yo.
干嘛
Whatcha up to?
没事
Nothin'.
你好像在拍自己骑着
'Cause it looks like you were filming yourself
电子世界争霸战炫光坐骑出逃游戏网格
on a "Tron" light cycle escaping the game grid.
电子世界争霸战 迪斯尼1982年出品的超现实主义科幻题材影片
你看过电子世界争霸战
You've seen "Tron."
十六次
16 times.
我妈妈都有点担心了
My mom's actually kinda worried.
嗨 我是亚当
Hi, I'm Adam.
我是查德...克伦普
I'm Chad... Kremp.
我们刚搬到街对面
We just moved in across the street.
想不想看看我的炫光坐骑
You wanna check out my light cycle?
好的 耶
Sure. Yeah.
就这样 我有了一个新邻居和好朋友
And just like that, I had a new neighbor and best friend.
虽然我们有很多相同的地方
Even though we had so much in common,
我们的家人却大相径庭
our families couldn't have been more different.
克伦普一家细语轻声的
The Kremps were soft-spoken...
嗨 查德能玩会儿吗
Hi. Can chad play?
查德 宝贝 你的朋友在这儿呢
Chad, honey, your friend is here.
戈德堡家喜欢大吼大叫
And the Goldbergs liked to yell.
嗨 亚当能玩会儿吗
Hi. Can Adam play?
亚当 赶紧给我滚下来
Adam! Get your ass down here!
克伦普家有个美丽的花店...
The Kremps owned a fancy flower shop...
这儿 亚当
Here, Adam.
把这些带回家送给你妈妈吧
Why don't you take these home to your mother?
为什么
Why?
戈德堡家拥有一个折扣家具店
The Goldbergs owned a discount furniture store.
嘿...离那家具远点儿
Hey... Get off the furniture!
我还得拿这玩意儿卖钱呢
I gotta sell this crap.
这就是克伦普家典型的周六下午...
This was a typical Saturday afternoon at the Kremps'...
刚才挺厉害的 不是么 儿子
Put a little pepper on that one, didn't you, son?
从最厉害的人那学来的
I learned from the best.
嘿 给我的主场球队来点柠檬水
Hey, lemonade for my home team.
而戈德堡家的周六下午
While a Saturday afternoon at the Goldbergs'
更像是这种...
Looked more like this...
搞什么鬼 巴里・戈德堡
What the hell? Barry Goldberg,
立刻把你的屁股从那棵树上挪开
you get your butt out of that tree right now!
什么傻瓜会被困到一棵树上
What kind of moron gets stuck in a tree?
亚当说我爬不了那么高
Adam said I couldn't climb this high.
- 我爬给他看看 - 你显然做到了
- I showed him! - You sure did.
你要是不赶紧下来
If you don't come down right now,
我这就去拿水管
I am gonna go get the hose!
你不会喷你的儿子的
You're not gonna spray our son.
- 停 - 埃里卡
- Stop! - Erica--
别玩那个球了!
Enough with the ball!
马上就拿软管来了
The hose is the way to go.
额 他是个把自己困在树上的傻瓜
Um, he's the idiot that got himself stuck up there.
我会试着够到他
I'll try and catch him--
嘿 邻居 嗨
Hey, neighbors! Hi!
我们来办一场书上的烧烤会吧 怎么样
We have got to get that barbecue on the books, don't we?
- 绝对的 - 好极了
- Definitely. - That'd be great.
- 他是个傻瓜 - 的确
- He's a moron! - He is!
- 嗨 - 这就是"戈德堡家的第一印象"
- Hi! - And that's what you'd call "a Goldberg first impression."
戈德堡一家 第一季08集
很久之前还没有手机时
Long before cell phones,
只有一条电话线...
you only had one phone line...
它就是所有问题的根源
And it was the source of all problems.
- 挂电话 挂电话 - 等会 蕾妮
- Get off the phone. Get off the phone. - Hold on, Lainey.
- 挂电话 - 我在讲话
- Get off the phone. - I'm talking!
走开 不然我就拣你脑袋上软的地方揍一拳
Go away, or I'll punch you in the soft part of your skull.
妈妈让你别打我那儿
Mom told you not to punch me there.
给我电话 我要打个重要的电话
Now give me the phone. I got an important call to make.
真的 什么这么重要
Really? What's so important?
我要给罗杰打电话
I gotta call Roger.
他借了我的曲棍球棍
He borrowed my hockey stick,
而我在外面发现了个黄蜂窝
and I found a hornet's nest out back.
你的生活实在是悲哀简单
Your life is so sad and simple.
去
Go.
不 挂电话
No. Get off the phone.
- 挂电话 挂电话 - 嘿 知道么...
- Get off the phone. Get off the phone-- - Hey, you know...
我在和你们那么大的时候 喜欢收音机
When I was your age, I was a radio man
有103频道 和法国人英国人一起
with the 103rd, working with the French and the British.
我们尽管共享一条线路
We shared one line,
还是一起设法赢了战争
and we still managed to win the war.
请别再讲这些故事了行么
Can you please stop with these stories?
这儿有个现实问题
This is a real life situation here.
爸 我们需要第二根电话线
Dad, we gotta get a second phone line.
两根电话线
Two phone lines?
你以为这是哪儿 白宫吗
What does this look like-- the White House?
另一根电话线 这可能吗
A second line-- is that even possible
所有的线交叉出入
with all those wires crossing in and out?
它们能做到吗
Can they even do that?
当波普斯理解不了电话的工作原理时
While pops couldn't understand how the phone worked,
我妈妈不理解为什么克伦普一家
my mom couldn't understand why the Kremps
一直躲着她的烧烤会邀请
kept ducking her barbecue invitation.
这太荒谬了
This is getting ridiculous.
我对克伦普一家一直很友好...
I have been nothing but nice to the Kremps...
而他们显然在疏远我们
And they're clearly blowing us off.
我的意思是 他们为什么要躲开我们呢
I mean, why would they want to avoid us?
你干什么了
What did you do?
什么
What?
你听到我说的了 你...干什么了
You heard me. What... Did you do?
我都没和他们说过一句话
I haven't said a word to those people.
行了 这就是问题所在
Well, that's the problem right there.
你不友好 你都不跟他们打招呼
You're not friendly, you don't say "Hi,"
你穿着内裤浇院子
You water the yard in your underpants.
这让人不舒服
It's disconcerting.
看起来像是你存心要把人们赶走
It's like you're trying to drive people away.
那是因为我真的想把别人赶走
That's because I am trying to drive people away.
好吧 这就是为什么你没朋友 默里
Well, that is why you have no friends, Murray.
家里人满为患
I live in a house full of people
一刻都不让人清闲
who won't leave me the hell alone.
有这些朋友足够了
That's all the friends I need.
好吧 你可能不想要朋友 可是我想要
Well, you may not want friends, but I do.
给我过去
Go over there and apologize
为自己不穿裤子脾气暴躁向人家道歉
for being a pantsless grumpy pants.
我要为做我自己向人家道歉
I should apologize for being me?
对
Yes!
嗨 我是 呃  对面街的默里・戈德堡
Hi. I'm, uh, Murray Goldberg from across the street.
只是想过来正式地介绍自己
Just thought I'd come over and formally introduce myself.
查尔斯・克伦普 很高兴认识你
Charles Kremp. Pleasure to meet you.
- 进来吧 - 噢 好 谢谢
- Come on in. - Oh, okay. Thank you.
这个地方真好闻
This place smells great!
是栀子花香
It's the gardenias.
这是职业兴趣 我是个花店老板
It's a perk of the job. I'm a florist.
- 噢 工作怎么样 - 不错
- Oh, how about that? - That's right.
我们浴室里有一个...一个花洒
We have a... a flower spray that we keep in the bathroom.
也不错
It tries.
但是我想说的是
But the point is,
我是过来邀请你去烧烤的
I am here to invite you to a barbecue.
对 那... 那件事
Yes, that... That situation.
这么说...还真有事 是吗
So... It is a situation, huh?
今后
From now on,
我会尽量 呃
I will try and, uh,
出门的时候穿好裤子
wear pants when I go outside.
尽量
Try.
实话说 呃... 我...我老婆弗吉尼亚...
To be honest, um... My...my wife Virginia...
她有点敏感
She can be a little sensitive,
还有 呃...
and, uh...
怎么说呢... 你老婆吓到她了
How to put this... your wife scares her.
什么
What?
那天 我爸终于要做一件
That day, my father finally got to do something
他打结婚那天就一直梦寐以求的事...
he had been waiting for since the day he got married...
指责别人
Be right!
是你
It's you!
- 什么 - 你听着
- What? - You heard me.
不是我的问题
It's not me that's the problem.
是你
It's you!
我做错什么了
What did I do?
噢... 你吓到那女的了
Oh... You scare the woman.
狠狠地吓了她一把
Scare her but good.
太荒唐了
That is ridiculous.
我除了对她很热情之外什么也没做
I have never been anything but cordial to her.
她怎么会不喜欢我
How can she not like me?
你大叫 呃 你在屋里大叫 在屋外也大叫
You yell. Uh, you yell inside, you yell outside.
还有很明显 你爬到垃圾车上
And apparently, you climbed up on a garbage truck
对着清洁工大叫
to yell at the garbage man.
他车已经开到半路
And he drove halfway down the block
你还挂在车后
with you hanging off the back.
所以然后他就开回来把我们的旧水槽收走了
And then he drove back and picked up our old sink.
不客气
You're welcome.
随你怎么说 贝弗
Explain it any way you want to, Bevy.
那女的不喜欢你
That woman no likey you.
但有人不喜欢我妈的这个念想
But the idea of someone not liking my mom
却不会就这样消失
was not gonna fly.
贝弗莉・戈德堡一心想
Beverly Goldberg prided herself on
成为万人迷
being loved by all.
她会为此大费周章
And she couldn't have it any other way.
喔喔 弗吉尼亚
Whoo-hoo! Virginia!
她把暴走变成了跟踪
She turned power walking into power stalking.
我刚刚没看见你
I didn't see you there.
噢 我不知道你也暴走
Oh. I didn't know you power walked.
真巧啊
What a coincidence.
我每天都走
I do it every day.
才没有
She didn't.
好吧 我要..继续了
Well, I should... Keep moving.
- 我刚达到燃脂峰值 所以... - 噢 不错
- I just hit my peak burn period. So... - Oh, good stuff,
不错 听着...
good stuff. Listen...
我想我们一开始处得不是很愉快
I feel like we got off on the wrong foot,
但我相信我们会成为好朋友的
and I know we're gonna be great friends.
所以 求你了 过来烧烤吧
So please, come over for a barbecue.
可以
Sure.
当然可以 我会通知你的
Sure, I'll let you know.
现在吗 好 呃 周六怎么样
Now? Okay, uh, how about Saturday?
我感觉周六会下雨
I think it's supposed to rain on Saturday.
太好了 就周六了 说定了
Great, Saturday it is. Mark it down.
你不用带什么东西
You don't have to bring anything
就带着开放的态度 还有四个配菜
except an open mind and four sides.
不 带一个也行 如果你想的话
No. Just one side, if you want.
好的
Okay.
- 我要继续了 - 好 我来带头
- I'm gonna keep moving. - Okay, I'll lead.
噢 啊 抽筋 抽筋 抽筋
Oh! Aah! Cramp, cramp, cramp.
好吧 周六 期待着留下美好回忆吧
Okay, Saturday it is. Prepare to make some memories.
当我妈在努力尝试跟克伦普
While my mom was trying to make a connection
交朋友时
with Mrs. Kremp...
我哥却想给自己交朋友
My brother was hoping to make a connection of his own.
你好 大男孩
Hey, there, big boy.
我是976鼓励热线
You've reached 9-7-6-fox.
很高兴你的来电
I'm glad you called.
和车上的辣妹倾谈... 请按一
To speak with a hot girl in a car...press one.
和飞机上的荡妇倾谈... 请按二
To speak with a nasty girl on a plane...press two.
什么鬼...喂
What the... Hello?
挂电话
Hang up.
Hang up!
挂电话
说真的 你是在打976热线吗
Seriously, you're calling 9-7-6 numbers?
这是与一个朋友的私密谈话
That's a personal call with a friend!
给我
Gimme that.
你选择了情色泛舟行
You've selected erotic boat ride.
噢 伙计
Oh, man.
你被抓现行了
You are so busted.
别跟爸爸告状 求你了
Don't tell dad, please.
我可以做任何事
I'll do anything.
我让你连续打一个星期的电话
I'll give you one week of uninterrupted phone time.
那还挺难取舍的
Hmm, that's hard to pass up.
爸爸 巴里在给976热线打电话
Dad! Barry's calling 9-7-6 numbers!
什么
What?!
打这种电话要5.99美元一分钟的
Those calls are like $5.99 a minute.
前两分钟是免费的
The first two minutes are free,
我从来没超过两分钟
and I never go beyond the second minute.
我用的是拼字游戏里的计时器
I use the timer from Boggle.
很管用的
It's legit.
噢 你还想着管用
Oh, you want legit?
- 一个月不许打电话 - 神马
- No phone for a month! - What?!
- 全怪你 - 你想去玩划艇
- This is your fault! - How is it my fault
怎么也怪我了
that you want to get frisky in a rowboat?
我可没这么打算
That wasn't the selection I was gonna make.
你麻烦大了
Okay, now you're in trouble.
你儿子老是拨打色情电话
Your son has been calling smut numbers.
我可不管 我有要事要跟你谈谈
I don't care. I have something very important to tell you.
克伦普一家要过来一起吃烧烤了
The Kremps are coming over for a barbecue.
哇 这可是大事啊
Yes! That is big!
我们应该专注于这个而不是抓住我不放对吧
Now let's focus on this and not my thing.
再说点儿关于这个盛大的烧烤活动吧
Tell us more about this important barbecue.
等等 你是说克伦普全家都来
Wait, are we talking about all the Kremps here,
那些男孩也会来吗
like, the boys, too--
那个跟亚当同岁的男孩 还有那个跟我同岁
The one that's Adam's age, and the one that's my age
棕发蓝眼的那个
with sandy brown hair and blue eyes?
尽管那女人被你吓到了
You still want to have a barbecue with these people,
你还是想跟他们一起烧烤吗
even though that woman's terrified of you?
不再会啦
Not anymore.
今早我起床后
I woke up early this morning,
徒步追了她两英里路
followed her for 2 miles on foot,
赶上她并且说服她
then chased her down and convinced her
我没什么好害怕的
there's nothing scary about me.
拜托 这周本来很清闲的
Come on. I had nothing planned this weekend.
是个完美周末
It was perfect.
那你现在有事做啦 你得表现的热情
Well, now you do. And you will be warm
好客 行行好
and inviting, and so help me god,
最好不要在客人面前睡着了
you better not fall asleep in front of these people.
好 我们开始准备吧
Okay! Let's get cookin'!
脱下 赶紧脱下来
Off. Take it off.
这可是打破僵局的绝活儿
It's an icebreaker...
有时候用途还不止这个
Sometimes more.
老爸 他们可是有教养的人
Dad, these are good people.
我们得注意言行举止
We need to be on our best behavior.
不能说黄色笑话 打油诗 讲黄段子之类的
That means no dirty jokes, no limericks, no lewd comments.
听起来真是个无聊的聚会
This party sounds like a real drag.
至于你们呢
As for the rest of you,
不要大喊大叫 不要骂人 不要打架
no yelling, no cursing, no fighting.
记住我的话
Mark my words.
这一定是后院烧烤会有史以来
This will be the best backyard barbecue
最好的后院烧烤会
in the history... Of backyard barbecues.
也可能不是
Or not.
这将会是一个跟克伦普一家共度的风雨交加的周末
It was gonna be a very stormy weekend with the Kremps.
尽管烧烤期间下起了雨
Even though it rained during the big barbecue,
也没有阻止我跟查迪特
didn't stop me and Chad
热情满腔地唱"帝国反击战"
from reciting "Empire Strikes Back" by heart.
# 不不 这不是真的 #
No, no, that's not true.
# 这是不可能的 #
That's impossible.
也没有阻止我姐姐跟德鲁・克伦普热络起来
It also didn't stop my sister from warming up to Drew Kremp,
没有妨碍我老爸打瞌睡
or my dad from falling asleep,
也没有打消我妈妈跟弗吉尼亚
or my mom from trying to get Virginia
套近乎
to warm up to her.
- 我给你倒了点酒 - 你说什么
- I brought you some wine. - What?!
我给你倒了点酒
I brought you some wine.
抱歉 我听不清
I'm sorry. I can't hear you.
噢 抱歉 我天生声音轻柔
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm so naturally soft-spoken.
我给你倒了点酒
I brought you some wine.
有人要热狗吗
Okay, who needs dogs?
真是太感谢了
Thank you so much. Look--
瞧 你把面包都烤热了
Oh, you warmed my buns.
bun 还有臀部的意思
嗯
Yes.
这么大根火腿我都不知道能不能吃完
I don't know if I can handle all this meat.
她这是在跟我开玩笑吗
Is she kidding me with this?
别瞎想
Just go.
大家都玩得不怎么高兴
No one was really enjoying themselves...
除了巴里
Except for Barry.
你好啊 姐姐
Hello, sister.
真是个适合烧烤的好天气啊 对吧
Perfect day for a barbecue, isn't it?
怪咖 外面下大雨呢
No, weirdo. It's pouring outside.
噢 真是抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我是说 这真是个复仇的好时机啊
I meant, it's a perfect day for revenge.
德鲁・克伦普真是太可口了
Drew Kremp is so delicious.
真想把他蘸着牛奶吃掉
I want to dunk him in a glass of milk and eat him up.
搞什么啊
What the hell?
你竟然录制我的私人通话
You recorded my private phone call?
真好笑 我只是碰巧在你打电话的时候
Funny... How I just happened to pick up
拿起了听筒
when you were on the phone.
我要不要在大伙儿面前把剩余的录音播放出来娱乐一下呢
Should I play the rest for the guests we're entertaining?
好吧 你赢了
Okay, you win.
你随时都可以打电话 可以了吧
You can use the phone whenever you want, okay?
千万不要放出来 拜托了
Just please don't play it, I'm begging you.
正像我之前求你不要告诉老爸的时候呢
Kind of like how I begged you not to tell dad, huh?
或许你可以提醒我一下这是怎么发生的呢
Perchance, can you remind me how that turned out?
少这样阴阳怪气说话了 把这该死的磁带给我
Will you stop talking like that and just give me the  damn tape?
- 不给 - 你给我
- No. - Just give it--
才不给你 放手
Not giving it to you. Stop it!
别给脸不要脸啊
You're embarrassing yourself.
- 给我 - 松手
Give it-- stop!
松手
Stop!
"埃里卡・克伦普"听起来不错吧
I mean, doesn't "Erica Kremp" sound perfect?
等我们结婚了 我们要一起滑雪
When we get married, we're gonna ski
要整天说法语 还会生出超级漂亮的金发小宝贝
and speak French all day and have super blonde kids.
-  噢 我的天 - 这可不是我所计划的
- Oh, dear. - That... Was not the plan.
那你计划干嘛
What was the plan?
你还打算干嘛
What was the plan?!
孩子们 够了
Kids, enough!
他们其实不是这样的
This is so out of character for them.
- 我要打你 - 走开
- Let me punch you! - Get off me!
孩子们 我教过你们不要打对方私处
Kids, I told you not to punch each other in the privates.
你俩都不许用电话了
No phone for either of you.
别动
Stop moving!
给我吃
Eat it!
默里 你给我醒过来
Murray, wake the up!
唔 你看 天色已晚
Well, you know, it's-- it's getting late.
我们该回去了 好吧 再见啦 玩得很开心
We should probably head out. Okay. Bye-bye now.  Good time.
一周过去了 我都没见到查德
A week went by, and I hadn't seen Chad.
谢天谢地 Pops总在我需要的时候及时出现
Thankfully, pops was always there when I needed him.
好的 准备好了吗
Okay, and we're rolling.
开始
Action!
我第一句台词是什么
What's my first line?
哦 拜托 没开玩笑吧
Oh, come on, seriously?
你把果汁喷趣酒弄到衣服上了
You got fruit punch on your suit?
哦 没关系的
Oh, it's okay.
我...我赋予了这个角色很多想法
I...I've given the character a lot of thought.
这个机器人很喜欢果汁喷趣酒
This robot loves fruit punch.
他是个脏兮兮的机器人
He's a messy robot.
我说过了 你不是个机器人
I told you, you're not a robot.
或者是...他不进计算机世界
Or... Instead of him going to a computer world,
让他去果汁世界怎么样
how about he goes to a juice world?
根本没有果汁世界这种东西
There's no such thing as a juice world!
但是计算机世界就是真的吗
But computer worlds are real?
赶紧的吧
Just go.
我不明白为什么机器人就不能喜欢果汁
I don't know why a robot can't like juice.
查德今天去哪儿了
Where's Chad today?
呃... 我... 我觉得他没空
Uh... I...I don't think he's available.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他妈妈说了
His mom just said
我们暂时不能一起玩
we can't play together for a while.
什么
What?!
那女人疯了
The nerve of that woman.
我现在就过去那边
I'm marching over there right now
好好教训她一顿
and giving her a piece of my mind.
不 等等 她最怕的就是你
No! Wait! Your mind is the part that scares her the most.
答应我 别去那儿
Promise me you won't go over there.
求你了 你只会让事情变得更糟
Please. You'll just make it worse.
好吧 小可爱
All right, love bug.
我不会去那儿 我保证
I won't go over there, I promise.
我妈说到做到
My mom was a woman of her word.
她没去那儿
She didn't march over there.
但是 她打了电话
Instead, she called.
你好 这里是克伦普家
Hello. You've reached the Kremps.
请留言 祝您有愉快的一天
Please leave a message and have a wonderful day.
弗吉尼亚 我是贝弗莉・戈德堡 快接电话
Virginia, it's Beverly Goldberg. Pick up.
哦 拜托 我看到你躲在窗帘后面了
Oh, please, I see you lurking behind the curtain
你在自己家 跟个怪人似的
like a weirdo in your own home.
能快点接起电话吗
Would you pick up the phone already?
太抱歉了 我刚刚在洗澡
So sorry, I was just in the shower.
别废话 告诉我为啥亚当不能跟查德一起玩
Cut the crap and tell me why Adam can't play with Chad.
抱歉 我只是...
I'm sorry. Look, I just...
觉得我们是风格迥异的人...
Think that we have different styles--
在孩子面前的
Different ways of speaking
说话方式不同
in front of our children,
总体上是...
and just generally...
世界上两种不同的存在
Different ways of being in the world.
好的
Fine.
如果查德不能跟亚当一起玩
If Chad can't play with Adam,
亚当也不能跟查德一起玩
Adam can't play with Chad.
我也不会介意你是否喜欢我
And I could give a hoot whether or not you like me
因为我有一大堆朋友 知道吗
because I have buttloads of friends, okay?
一大堆
Buttloads.
我...遵守诺言了
I... Kept my promise.
我没有去她家
I didn't go over there.
就这样
And just like that,
我妈扼杀了我跟查德的友谊
my mom had hung up on my friendship with Chad.
但是我们并不是唯一玩过界的小孩
But we weren't the only ones getting our lines crossed.
我哥和我姐关于电话的战争
My brother and sister's battle over the phone
第二天仍在继续
had stretched on another day.
但是巴里很快发现 战争
But what Barry would soon realize was the fight
即将在屋外进行
was about to be taken outside.
我是认真的 蕾妮
I'm serious, Lainey.
德鲁・克伦普什么都听见了
Drew Kremp heard everything.
我打算辍学 然后逃出镇子
I'm thinking of quitting school and skipping town.
完蛋了 你彻底完蛋了
Busted! You are so busted,
我会告诉爸妈 胜者还是我
and I'm telling, and Barry wins.
爸妈说我们不能用屋里的电话
Mom and dad said we couldn't use the phone in the house.
从技术层面上说...我已经不在屋里了
Technically... I'm outside the house.
真是高明
That's very intelligent.
给我 我要打电话
Give it to me! I gotta make a call!
不行 这是我的主意
No way! It was my idea!
- 快给我 - 给我停下
- Just give it to me! - Stop!
蕾妮 别挂
Lainey, hold on!
把它...给...我
Give it... To... Me.
你把它弄坏了
You broke it!
也许你该拨打976新电话
Maybe you should call 9-7-6-new-phone.
也许你该拨打...
Maybe you should call...
闭嘴
Shut up!
你搞笑呢
Are you kidding me?!
我做过的事都不后悔
I stand by what I did.
天哪
God!
为什么我们会变成这样
Why are we like this?
因为我们是一家人
'Cause we're a family.
家人就是这样的
That's what a family does.
我们只会打架 我已经精疲力尽了
All we ever do is fight, and it's exhausting.
等等
Wait.
你不会把泥巴扔回我脸上呀
You're not gonna throw mud back in my face?
我该怎么办
What do I do?
告诉我 我该怎么办
Tell me, what do I do?
随后的一周 我妈和弗吉尼亚・克伦普
For the next week, my mom and Virginia Kremp
都刻意避开对方 但是在一个小镇子里
avoided each other. But in a small town,
你不可能躲着一个人很久
you can only avoid someone for so long.
我知道一定有什么不对劲
I knew something was wrong
因为当我咬了一口松饼时
because when I bit into the eclair,
那味道就像是酸奶油和泡菜
it tasted like sour cream and pickles.
如果它们坏了 那就是你的表坏了
If they went bad, they went bad on your watch.
我知道你为什么会这么想
I can see why you would think that.
通常我不会...绝不会 这样大惊小怪
And normally I would never... Ever, ever make a fuss.
但是我买回来这些东西还不到二十四小时
But I did purchase these less than 24 hours ago,
收据还在这儿呢
and I still have the receipt.
这些东西不能退
I'm not taking these back!
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?!
我妈可能会对弗吉尼亚妥协
My mom may have been able to give up on Virginia,
但是她绝不会背弃自己
but she couldn't give up on who she was.
戈德堡太太
Mrs. Goldberg,
我...我不知道你俩之前认识
I...I didn't know you two knew each other.
废话我们当然认识 我们可是邻居
Damn right we do. We're neighbors.
现在... 要么去给她拿些新做的松饼
Now... Go back and get her some fresh eclairs.
要么你就是还想上演...
Or would you like a repeat...
生日蛋糕事件的惨败
of the birthday cake fiasco?
是谁在一个十岁孩子的生日蛋糕上
Who writes "sorry for your loss"
写了"为你们的损失感到抱歉"
on a 10-year-old's birthday cake?
- 那只是个小疏忽 而且维克多已经被开除了 - 是啊
- It was a mistake, and Victor was let go. - Yeah.
但对这个店来说可是倒霉的日子
Well, that was a dark day for this store.
不过它还有可能更倒霉
But it could get a lot darker.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
抱歉 女士 我会马上解决的
Sorry, ma'am. I'll fix you right up.
我知道我刚才又大声喧哗 引起围观了
I know I just made a big, loud scene.
这就是我的作风
It's just what I do.
开门 开门 亲爱的
Knock, knock. Honey?
你在里面吗
Are you in there?
走开 我不想和你说话
Go away. I don't wanna talk to you.
你是对的 我该给你一些空间
You're right. I should give you some space.
最起码把门关上 别开灯
At least close the door, and don't turn on the lights.
黑暗是我唯一的朋友
Darkness is my only friend.
亚当 我很抱歉
Adam, I am so sorry.
你当然该感到抱歉 看看我现在的样子
You should be sorry! Look at me!
我穿着一身夜光弹力紧身衣
I'm in a glow-in-the-dark unitard!
查德是它为我带来的唯一的朋友...
And Chad was the only friend that got me...
还有谁能有这个
Who got this!
而你却毁掉了这一切...
And you just had to ruin it...
就为了这世上有个人
Just because one person in this world
不喜欢你
didn't like you.
亲爱的...
Sweetie...
你对我来说才是最重要的
You're the one that matters.
我宁愿所有人都讨厌我
I'd rather have nobody like me
但我就是不愿看到你永远生我的气
than have you be mad at me forever.
不是永远 只是一个半月
Not forever, just for about a month and a half.
好吧...
Well...
让我试试能不能缩短这个时间
Let's see if I can shorten that up just a bit.
嗨
Yo.
你在做什么
Whatcha doin'?
没什么
Nothing.
想不想一起拍完我们的电影
Want to finish our movie?
想啊 你呢
Yeah. Do you?
- 妈的 当然 - 查德 别说脏话
- Hell, yeah. - Chad, "H" word.
对不起
Sorry.
太棒了
Cool.
"H"词到底是什么
What the hell's the "H" word?
那么 我想明天我们可以一起暴走
So I was thinking tomorrow we could go for a power walk.
然后你可以来我家一起分小松饼吃
And then you could come over and we could split an eclair.
或者我现在就可以去
Or I could come over right now,
我们就能各吃各的小松饼了
and we could each have our own eclair.
嗯... Beverly Goldeberg 你可真不咋样
Mm... Beverly Goldberg, you are bad.
我是不咋样 我可是最差劲的
I am bad. I am the worst.
就这样吧 走吧
Let's do it. Let's do it.
好的
Okay.
就这样 这世上唯一
And just like that, the one person out there
不喜欢我老妈的人成了她最要好的朋友
who didn't like my mom became her best friend.
就连我老爸
Even my dad,
虽然总是以没有朋友自居
who prided himself on having no friends,
但也开始有交朋友的念头了
started to come around to the idea.
嗨
Yo.
干嘛呢
Whatcha doin'?
呃... 没什么
Uh... Nothin'.
我不知道你是否感兴趣 不过 嗯...
I don't know if you're interested, but, um...
我这有老鹰队的赛季票...
I got eagles season tickets...
在中场
50 yard line.
你礼拜天有空吗
You around Sunday?
当然
Yeah!
看着克伦普家的孩子们和睦相处
Watching the Kremp kids get along
激发了巴里和埃里卡去尝试一些新的疯狂的事...
inspired Barry and Erica to try something new and crazy...
他们彼此留意对方
Look out for each other.
嘿 查德
Hey, Chad.
你不是想打赌我爬不上你家院子里的树吗
You want to bet I can't climb the tree in your yard?
是的
Yeah!
我们彼此学到了很多
We learned a lot from each other.
我们教会了他们
We taught them it was okay
偶尔抬高嗓音也没什么不可以
to raise your voice now and then.
我要的是那种薄如纸片的
I asked for paper-thin.
而你给我的...
You gave me slices...
却有我的拇指那么厚... 简直让人无法接受
Thick as my thumb... not acceptable.
在他们学着怎样更像戈德堡一家的同时
While they learned how to be more like the Goldbergs,
我们也学着怎样更像克伦普家的人
we learned to be a little more like the Kremps.
埃里卡 有你电话
Erica, telephone.
什么 老妈 按一下那个按钮
What? Push the button, mom.
一点都不难
It's not hard.
- 埃里卡 - 我到底要教你多少次怎么用啊
- Erica... - How many times do I have to show you how this works?
这个该死的东西该怎么用呀
How does this stupid thing work?
- 埃里卡 电... - 对着盒子讲话
- Erica, telep... - Talk into the box!
- 埃里卡 电话 - 哈喽
- Erica! Telephone! - Hello?
- 快接那个该死的电话 - 你怎么了 老妈
- Pick up the damn phone! - What's the matter with you? Mom?
是的 我们和克伦普家的人不同...
Yep, we were different than the Kremps...
不是更好 也不是更糟...
Not better, not worse...
仅仅是... 不同
Just... Different.
跟你说过了 我能再做到的
Told you I could do it again.
你太愚蠢了 居然怀疑我的能力
You're so stupid for doubting me.
哦 虽然巴里不帮我们解决纷争
Oh, though Barry didn't help our case.
好的 各位 今天我们要再现
Okay, folks. Today we're re-enacting
"帝国反击战"的一些情景 你准备好了吗
some "Empire Strikes Back." Are you ready?
老兄 你确定要这样吗
Dude, are you sure about this?
哦 我确定 继续录制
Oh, I'm sure. Keep it rolling.
发生了什么
What's goin' on?
哦 你为什么总是玩这种低级游戏
Oh, why do you always do this crap?
我可是你的父亲
I'm your father!
不... 那不是真的
No... That's not true.
不可能
That's impossible!
"不可能"是什么意思
What do you mean "impossible"?
- 妈的快滚开 - 快跑
- Get the hell outta here! - Run!